gumtree.sg 2013-12-12

# Gumtree Help Desk - Gumtree Privacy Policy

### Gumtree Privacy Policy

Solution **Gumtree Privacy Policy**

On August 14, 2012, the Gumtree privacy policy was updated. Please take a few minutes and review the revised Privacy Policy. If you have any questions, please [**_contact us_**](http://gumtreehelp.com/sg/index.php?a=add). If you do not accept this revised Privacy Policy, Gumtree may not be able to provide you with our service. Accordingly, you may close your account [**_here_**](http://gumtreehelp.com/sg/index.php?a=add). 

This Privacy Policy describes how the Gumtree website, tools, applications, and services (“Gumtree”) handle your personal information. Gumtree collects, uses, and shares personal information to help Gumtree work and to keep Gumtree safe (details below). Gumtree only collects the minimum amount of personal information that it requires in order to help Gumtree work and to keep Gumtree safe. This policy is effective August 14, 2012. To see the previous policy, [**_click here_**](http://info.gumtree.com.au/privacypolicy/privacy_policy.pdf). 

**Binding Corporate Rules.** In addition to the privacy practices set out in this Privacy Policy, eBay Inc. has established a set of Corporate Rules (also referred to as Binding Corporate Rules), approved by a number of European Union privacy regulators. These Corporate Rules are a commitment by eBay Inc. to adequately protect your personal information regardless of where the data resides, and depending upon your location, may provide additional privacy rights through your privacy regulator or a court. If you would like additional information regarding the Corporate Rules, please contact us via the contact details below. 

**Collection.** Information posted on Gumtree is obviously publicly available. Our servers are located in the United States, European Union and elsewhere in the world where Gumtree has facilities. Therefore, if you choose to provide us with personal information, you are consenting to Gumtree's collection, use, disclosure of your personal information and to the transfer and storage of that information on our servers in the United States, the European Union, and elsewhere in the world where Gumtree has facilities. Gumtree collects and stores the following personal information: 

  * email address, phone numbers, physical contact information, and (depending on the service used) sometimes financial information (including credit card and billing information); 
  * computer sign-on data, statistics on page views, traffic to and from Gumtree and ad data (all through cookies - you can take steps to disable the cookies on your browser although this is likely to affect your ability to use the site); and 
  * other information, including users IP address and standard web log information. 

**Use.** Gumtree uses users' personal information to: 

    * provide our services; 
    * track, confirm and fulfil purchases; 
    * resolve disputes, collect fees, and troubleshoot problems; 
    * encourage safe trading and enforce our policies; 
    * customize, measure, and improve user experience and our services, content, and advertising; 
    * deliver targeted marketing, service updates, and promotional offers to you according to your preferences; 
    * do other things for users as described when Gumtree collects the information. 

**Disclosure.** Gumtree doesn't sell or rent users' personal information to third parties for their marketing purposes without users' explicit consent. Gumtree may disclose personal information to respond to legal requirements, enforce our policies, respond to claims that a posting or other content violates others' rights, or protect anyone's rights, property, or safety. Gumtree may also share personal information with: 

      * corporate affiliates who help detect and prevent potentially illegal acts and provide joint services. (Our corporate affiliates will market only to users who ask them to). 
      * service providers who help with our business operations. 
      * third-party websites and publishers so ads (or the content of the ads) published on Gumtree can also be published on a broader array of venues or information vehicles. 
      * Governmental or judicial bodies or agencies or other regulators to which eBay Inc. and/or Marktplaats B.V. is subject. 

**Communications and email tools.** You agree to receive marketing communications from us unless you tell us that you prefer not to receive such communications. If you don't wish to receive marketing communications from us, simply indicate your preference by following directions provided with the communication. You may not use our site or communication tools to harvest addresses, send spam or otherwise breach our Terms of Use, this privacy policy or other Gumtree policies in force from time to time. Gumtree may automatically scan and manually filter messages sent via our communication tools for malicious activity or prohibited content, but Gumtree does not permanently store such messages. Gumtree reserves the right to delay replies in cases of suspected fraudulent activity or violations of the [**_Gumtree Terms of Use_**](http://gumtreehelp.com/sg/knowledgebase.php?article=120) and/or to refuse to transmit messages. If you use our tools to send content to a friend, Gumtree doesn't permanently store your friends' addresses or use or disclose them for marketing purposes. To report spam from other users, please contact [**_customer support_**](http://gumtreehelp.com/sg/index.php?a=add)

**Access, Modification, and Deletion.** You can see, modify or erase most of your personal information by reviewing and modifying your posting or account status page, by signing on to [**_“My Gumtree”_**](http://singapore.gumtree.sg/c-ManageMyAds) or by contacting [**_customer support_**](http://gumtreehelp.com/sg/index.php?a=add) to review any personal information that Gumtree stores that is not available on Gumtree. There may be a charge associated with such requests but these will not exceed the amounts permitted by law. Gumtree deletes personal information when Gumtree no longer needs it for the purposes we described earlier. Gumtree retains personal information as permitted by law to resolve disputes, enforce our policies; and to assist with preventing any malicious use of Gumtree. If you have further questions, you can write to the Data Controller: 

Marktplaats B.V. - Privacy Policy Requests  
Wibautstraat 224-2, 1097 DN   
Amsterdam, The Netherlands 

or you may contact customer support via our website or by sending a fax to +1 647 723 7091. 

**Transfer of Personal Data to Other eBay Companies.** We may share your information with members of the eBay Inc. corporate family - like eBay or PayPal - to provide joint content and services (like registration, transactions and customer support), to help detect and prevent potentially illegal acts and violations of our policies, and to guide decisions about their products, services and communications. Members of our corporate family will use this information to send you marketing communications only if you've requested their services. 

**Security.** Gumtree uses lots of tools (encryption, passwords, physical security) to protect your personal information against unauthorized access and disclosure, but as you probably know, nothing's perfect, so Gumtree makes no guarantees or representations and gives no warranties as to the efficacy of the protection mechanisms referred to above. If you have chosen to register with Gumtree, your user registration is password protected to prevent unauthorised access. We recommend that you do not disclose your password to anyone. 

**Cookies.** Gumtree or our service providers may use "cookies" (small files placed on your hard drive) on certain of our pages to help analyze our web page flow; customize our services, content and advertising; measure promotional effectiveness, and promote trust and safety. A few important things you should know about cookies are that: 

        * Gumtree offers certain features that are available only through the use of cookies. 
        * Gumtree uses cookies to help identify you and maintain your signed-in status. 
        * You are always free to decline cookies if your browser permits, although doing so may interfere with your use of some of our sites or services. For more information on your choices about accepting cookies, consult your browser help function. 

Gumtree sometimes works with service providers who may place cookies on your computer to serve and measure the effectiveness of ads on our or our advertising partners' behalf and collect anonymous information about how you use websites owned by Gumtree and its affiliates. This information allows them to help us customize our content and advertising. Gumtree does not allow these companies to collect any personal information about you using these cookies. For more information about why Gumtree uses cookies, see [**_Cookies, Web Beacons, and Your Privacy_**](http://gumtreehelp.com/sg/knowledgebase.php?article=190). 

**General.** Gumtree may update this policy at any time, with updates taking effect when you next use the site or after 30 days, whichever is sooner. If Gumtree or our corporate affiliates are involved in a merger or acquisition, Gumtree may share personal information with another company, but this policy will continue to apply. Please send questions that you may have about the terms of this Privacy Policy to Gumtree [**_customer support_**](http://gumtreehelp.com/sg/index.php?a=add). 

Was this article helpful? [yes](javascript:void\(0\)) / [no](javascript:void\(0\))

Topic:  | Gumtree Policies  
---|---  
Date added:  | 2009-09-29 09:07:35  
Views:  | 934  
Rating (Votes): |  (6044)  

<< Go back
